Register of the Constantin Visoianu Papers, 1937-1960
Hoover Institution Archives
Constantin Visoianu Papers,
1937-1960
76103
Visoianu, Constantin, 1897-
5 manuscript boxes 2.1 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, speeches, writings, and photographs, relating to Romanian foreign relations, political developments in Romania, and anti-communist emigre activities
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1976.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Comitetul National Român.; Anti-communist movements--United States.; Communism.; Romanians in foreign countries.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Romania.; Romania.; Romania--Foreign relations.; Romania--Politics and government.; United States.; Statesmen--Romania.
Container List
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, n.d.
  - Speech regarding the problem of possible severance of relations between the Western powers and Soviet satellite countries, n.d. (Box 1.)
  - Talk given by C. Visoianu on the occasion of Union Day commemoration, January 24 (no year). In Romanian
- SUBJECT FILE, 1937-1952
  - "Le Corps Diplomatique a Moscou" (The Diplomatic Corps in Moscow), 1937 July (Box 1.)
  - Eastern European Conference resolution adopted concerning a declaration made by U.S. President D. Eisenhower regarding the satellite countries, 1952
  - Hitler, Adolf, letter to the King of Romania, 1940 July 15
  - Paris Peace Conference, 1946
    - "Romania at the Peace Conference," 1946
    - La Roumanie Devant la Conference de la Paix" (Romania at the Peace Conference), 1946
  - Peace treaty draft between Romania and the Allied Powers, 1946. In Romanian
  - Report on the way the first communist government was imposed in Romania by Molotov and his audiences with the King, reprint, New York Herald Tribune, 1947 October 23
  - Romanian elections, 1946 November
  - Romanian-Bulgarian relations, 1946 August
  - Romanian-Soviet relations, 1939-1940
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1949, 1951-1952
  - Austin, Warren R. (U.S. representative to the United Nations), 1949 (Box 2.)
  - Gallin, J., 1952
  - O'Hara, Gerald, Archbishop, 1951
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1949-1959. (Box 2.)
  Miscellaneous speeches and writings, 1949-59
- SUBJECT FILE, 1949-1955. The Romanian National Committee (Washington, D.C.)
  - "Persecution of Religion in Romania," 1949 November (Box 2.)
  - Reorganization, 1953-55
  - Statutes
  - "Suppression of Human Rights in Romania," 1949 September
- INCREMENT, 1977 May. (Box 2)
  Constantin Visoianu's private correspondence, 1955-1957